NEIL DEWING

SENIOR FRONT END DEVELOPER & UI/UX DESIGNER

roosterdesign.co.uk linkedin.com/in/roosterdesign



31/10/1982



Full UK, Clean

A meticulous, highly skilled Senior Front End Developer and UI/UX Designer with over 12 years of commercial experience in designing and building interactive, responsive websites and software applications.

I specialise in writing clean, accessible, HTML5 and LESS/SASS alongside JavaScript (ES5+) in an Agile environment. A highly adaptable, creative problem solver. I have a keen desire to improve and develop new skills with JS frameworks.



EDUCATION -

UNIVERSITY OF GLOUCESTERSHIRE

September 2001 - July 2006

BSc Degree in E-Commerce and Information

TEWKESBURY SIXTH FORM

September 1999 - June 2001

A-Level in Business Studies, Design & Technology & Geography



INTERESTS

Due to my passion for all things digital, I enjoy building on my knowledge of new programming languages and techniques which I can utilise to further my career and pass on this knowledge to those around me. In my spare time I enjoy Squash, Darts and Bowling. I'm also bit of a movie nut and I co-run a YouTube channel dedicated to another passion of mine, Photography and Videography.



Examples of my work can be found at roosterdesign.co.uk and jbandg.co.uk.



- HTML5 / CSS3
- LESS / SASS / Bootstrap
- Vanilla JavaScript (ES5+) / jQuery
- Experience working with React / Gatsby / Angular 2+ / Vue
- GraphQL / Rest API
- Experience working with ASP.NET / C#
- NPM / Gulp / Grunt / Babel / Webpack
- GIT / TFS Version Control
- Agile / Scrum / Kanban
- CSS Methodologies (BEM / Atomic)
- Umbraco / Wordpress

- Mobile first responsive web design
- WCAG / WAI-ARIA Accessibility
- UI / UX Design
- Wireframing & Prototyping
- A/B & Multivariate testing
- Multilingual Websites
- Visual Studio / VS Code / Sublime Text / Command Line
- Sketch
- Adobe CC
- Jira / Confluence / Trello
- MS Office / Mac/ PC



EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

HOLLAND & BARRETT Front End Developer (Contract) | Jan 2019 - March 2020

Holland & Barrett is the UK's Leading Health Retailer with both shops on the high street as well as websites for the UK, Netherlands, Belgium and Singapore.

Responsibilities include:

- Creating A/B and Multivariate tests using HTML5/CSS3/JavaScript (ES5+).
- Converting existing jQuery codebase to vanilla JavaScript (ES5+).
- Using Gatsby to create React based landing pages to improve speed and usability.
- Working with React components to replatform the current site and develop A/B tests.
- Using APIs and internal data sources to manipulate data and the DOM.
- Using pattern libraries and CI guidelines to design and develop create bespoke pages.
- Designing and creating landing pages using 3rd party CMS software.
- Working closely with BAs and Product Managers to shape the Digital CX roadmap.
- Reacting quickly to changes and bug fixes.
- Working with multilingual sites in both Dutch and French.
- Creating guidelines and standards for other Front End Developers to adhere to.
- Working with BEM/Atomic CSS methodologies.
- Using GULP, SCSS and Git to create a bespoke workflows.
- Ensuring all work passes WCAG accessibility guidelines.
- Helping/mentoring other developers and knowledge sharing.

TECH LABS UI/UX Designer & Front End Developer (Contract) | May 2017 - Dec 2018

Technical Labs is a Software Development company in Coventry, with a variety of clients as well as developing in-house software applications.

Responsibilities include:

- Writing clean, modular HTML5/CSS and JavaScript to deliver a responsive UI.
- Introducing BEM Methodology to all projects and training other developers on its use.
- Working in an Agile way, including daily stand-ups and Kanban boards.
- Working closely with C# ASP.NET developers to develop the front end.
- Working to tight deadlines and reacting quickly to requirement changes.
- Using Git to ensure the shared codebase is constantly up to date.
- Working with AngularJS to add basic interactivity to websites and software applications.
- Ensuring code falls back gracefully and is accessible to all users abiding by WCAG.

HPS UI/UX Designer & Front End Developer (Contract) | June 2015 - May 2017

HPS is a multi-disciplined marketing agency based in Marlow.

Responsibilities include:

- Acting as the lead Front End Developer on several large client sites including BMW, MINI, Rolls Royce and Orange.
- Translating designs into fully responsive websites optimised for mobile and search engines using HTML5/CSS3/JavaScript/jQuery.
- Ensuring websites conform to WCAG and are easily accessible to users across a range of devices.
- Using modular JavaScript to create bespoke interactive elements of the site and ensuring the site falls back gracefully.
- Introducing new techniques and best practices for the other Developers to adhere to, as well as introducing version control (Git).
- Tasked with developing the HPS client facing website, integrating with 3rd party APIs and a bespoke WordPress build.

INSPIRED THINKING GROUP Front End Developer (Contract) | April 2015 - June 2015

ITG is an award winning design agency based at Fort Dunlop, Birmingham.

Responsibilities include:

- Lead Front End Developer on a software application project for Heineken.
- $\odot \ \ \text{Creating bespoke, clean modular widgets combing HTML5/CSS3/JavaScript/jQuery and PHP.}$
- Keeping the central codebase up to date using Git.
- Working closely with PHP Back End developers, designers and project managers.
- Iterating quickly to changes within the product specification.

VALUE RETAIL Front End Developer (Contract) | June 2013 - Dec 2014

Value Retail is a luxury retail company, offering outlet shopping for the world's leading brands in 10 retail villages across Europe/Asia.

Responsibilities include:

- Lead Front End Developer tasked with creating bespoke online experiences including online gift card purchasing and Hotel booking.
- Working closely with Java Back End Developers, integrating my Front End templates with their code and utilising 3rd party APIs.
- Overcoming the challenges that comes with a multi-lingual site with 14 languages, creating scalable innovative solutions.
- Researching and implementing a new AngularJS framework and passing this knowledge on to the other team members.

• HOMESERVE Front End Developer (Contract) | Feb 2013 - May 2013

Homeserve provide home emergency insurance cover and domestic repairs to Britain's homes, based in Walsall.

Responsibilities include:

- Working closely with the creative department and a team of ASP.NET developers on updating the Homeserve website.
- Finding innovative solutions to several legal requirements and technical constraints and seamlessly integrating them to the site.
- Bringing the current Front End architecture up to date including clean, semantic HTML5 markup and LESS pre-processors.
- Raising standards with regards to writing clean reusable code as well as ensuring the front end of the site is pixel-perfect.

• ROOSTER DESIGN Freelance/Outsourcing | March 2011 - Feb 2016

Through my company established in 2010, I took a break from contracting to concentrate on my own clients and acting as an outsource resource for a number of local agencies allowing me to learn and develop new skills though working on a wide range of varying projects.

• WAA UI/UX Designer (Contract) | Jan 2011 - March 2011

WAA is an advertising and marketing agency with over 30 years' experience based in Sutton Coldfield.

Responsibilities include:

- Creating innovative wireframes and storyboards based on a client's requirements, and iterating on these until approval.
- Taking the wireframes and turning these into high fidelity UI designs for a number of client's websites and software applications.
- Offering my development experience to the developers ensuring quality levels remain high.

BIG COMMUNICATIONS Front End Developer (Contract/Freelance) | Oct 2011 - Oct 2012

BIG Communications is an award-winning creative agency based in Leicester with a wide variety of clients.

Responsibilities include:

- Senior developer working on a number of large clients including Boots, Thorpe Park, Jewson, Wolf Blass and JCB.
- Taking designs and turning them into WCAG compliant responsive websites.
- Building CMS websites using WordPress from the ground up, including custom widgets and functionality.

RAPPORT CREATIVE Senior Web Designer (Contract/Freelance) | Oct 2010 - Oct 2012

 $\hbox{BIG Communications is an award-winning creative agency based in Leicester with a wide variety of clients.}$

• BLUESKY INTERACTIVE Senior Web Designer (Permanent) | March 2007 - Sep 2010

Bluesky Interactive is a digital marketing agency specialising in franchise car dealers based in Learnington Spa.